Walter Sullivan Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Book Files, 1934-1997 (Box 66-127)
  - Black Holes: The Edge of Space, the End of Time (Box 68)
    - Permissions granted, 1977-1978 (Box 69)
    - Photographs and illustrations (Box 69)
      - Correspondence and permissions, 1975-1978 (Box 69)
      - Glossies, 1974-1979, undated (Box 69)
      - Miscellany, undated See also Container OV 2, same title, (1 folder) (Box 69, Box 70)
      - Working file, 1969-1978, (2 folders) (Box 70)
    - References, undated (Box 70)
    - Research and reference (Box 70)
      - Chapters 1-9, 1960-1978, undated, (9 folders) (Box 70)
      - Chapters 10-12, 1962-1978, undated, (7 folders) (Box 71)
      - Chapters 13-17, 1965-1978, undated, (7 folders) (Box 72)
      - Chapters 17-18, 1967-1978, undated, (2 folders) (Box 73)
      - General, 1967-1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Reviews, 1979-1982 (Box 73)
    - Titles and preface, undated (Box 73)
  - Continents in Motion: The New Earth Debate (Box 73)
    - Awards, 1975 (Box 73)
    - Contracts, 1975-1976 (Box 73)
    - Corrections, circa 1990, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Correspondence (Box 73)
      - Chapter check letters, 1971-1973 (Box 73)
      - General, 1971-1976, (3 folders) (Box 74)
      - Gitlin, Paul and McGraw Hill Publishing Co., 1972-1974 (Box 74)
      - Letters and gift recipients, 1970-1975, (3 folders) (Box 74)
      - Pending, 1957, 1971-1973 (Box 74)
    - Draft (Box 74)
      - Chapters 1-3, circa 1974, (9 folders) (Box 74)
      - Chapters 6-8, 10-13, circa 1974, (4 folders) (Box 75)
      - Chapters 17-21, circa 1974, (3 folders) (Box 76)
      - Introduction, circa 1974 (Box 76)
      - Magaziner and script, undated, (2 folders) (Box 76)
      - Marked copy, 1974, (3 folders) (Box 76)
      - Part two revised, undated (Box 77)
      - Replaced pages, undated (Box 77)
      - Review copy, undated, (4 folders); (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 77, Box 78, Box 79)
    - Drilling (Box 79)
      - "Dead" file, 1959-1973, undated, (4 folders) (Box 79)
      - Leg 1 through leg 12, 1969-1972, undated, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 79, Box 80)
      - Leg 14 and onward, 1971-1973, undated, (3 folders) (Box 80)
      - Mediterranean, 1970-1972, undated, (1 folder) (Box 80, Box 81)
      - Re-entry, 1970-1971 (Box 81)
      - Statistics, 1968-1972 (Box 81)
      - Summaries and clippings, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 81)
      - Technology, 1969-1972 (Box 81)
    - General articles, 1969-1971, undated (Box 81)
    - "Immanuel Velikovsky Reconsidered," Pensée (magazine), 1969-1971, undated (Box 81)
    - Index, undated (Box 82)
    - Le Pichon highlights, circa 1974, (3 folders) (Box 82)
    - Low grade, for casual checking, 1970-1972 (Box 82)
    - Miscellany, 1968-1976, undated See also Container OV 5, same title (Box 82)
    - Photographs and illustrations (Box 82)
      - Black and white, 1972-1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box 82)
      - Captions, circa 1973 (Box 82)
      - Chapters 1-2, 1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 82)
      - Chapters 3-7, 9-13, 1965-1973, undated, (11 folders) (Box 83)
      - Chapters 14-21, 1969-1973, undated, (9 folders) (Box 84)
      - "Dead" file, 1970-1971, undated (Box 84)
      - Miscellany (Box 84)
        - 1965-1973, undated See also Container OV 1 and OV 3, same title, (2 folders) (Box 84)
        - 1989, undated, (3 folders) (Box 85)
      - Not for second edition, 1973, undated (Box 85)
    - Promotional appearances, 1974-1976 (Box 85)
    - Reference lists, 1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 85)
    - References and revisions (Box 85)
      - Chapters 1-3, 1955-1959, 1965-1973, undated, (4 folders) (Box 85)
      - Chapters 3-6, 1938-1940, 1953-1973, undated, (10 folders) (Box 86)
      - Chapters 6-8, 10, 1959-1973, undated, (8 folders) (Box 87)
      - Chapters 11-13, 1967-1972, undated, (8 folders) (Box 88)
      - Chapters 13-16, 1961-1974, undated, (10 folders) (Box 89)
      - Chapters 16-18, 1961-1972, undated, (10 folders) (Box 90)
      - Chapters 19-20, 1967-1973, undated, (9 folders) (Box 91)
      - Chapters 20-21, 1967-1973, undated, (5 folders) (Box 92)
      - General, undated See also OV 2, same title (Box 92)
    - Research, 1971-1973, undated (Box 92)
    - Research inquiries pending, 1971-1973 (Box 92)
    - "Restless Earth" television special, 1972, undated (Box 92)
    - Reviews (Box 92)
      - 1974-1977 (Box 92)
      - 1974-1981, (2 folders) (Box 93)
    - Revisions, 1974-1992, (2 folders) (Box 93)
    - Titles and outline, circa 1972 (Box 93)
    - Update, resolved, 1971-1975, 1989, undated (Box 93)
  - Encyclopedia of Physics, forward, 1979-1980 (Box 93)
  - Great Ideas Today, "The Year's Advances in Physics and Technology," 1961, undated (Box 93)
  - Grolier Encyclopedia Yearbook, "International Geophysical Year," undated (Box 93)
  - Landprints: On the Magnificent American Landscape (Box 94)
    - "Air Guide" working file, 1980, undated (Box 94)
    - Appalachian Mountains, 1967-1982, undated, (3 folders) (Box 94)
    - Avalon approaching, 1978-1983 (Box 94)
    - Barrier islands, 1977-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 94)
    - Basin range, 1967, 1982-1983, 1989 (Box 94)
    - Bays, 1954, 1981-1982, 1990, undated (Box 94)
    - California, 1965, 1982 (Box 94)
    - Checkerboard, 1978-1983, undated, (1 folder) (Box 94, Box 95)
    - Connecticut, 1981, undated (Box 95)
    - Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (COCORP), New England soundings, 1983 (Box 95)
    - Corrections, 1985-1986 (Box 95)
    - Correspondence (Box 95)
      - Chapter reviews, 1981-1983, (3 folders) (Box 95)
      - General, 1970, 1980-1988 (Box 95)
      - Photographs (Box 95)
        - 1962-1967, 1977-1985, undated (Box 95)
        - 1980-1984 (Box 96)
      - State geologists, 1982 (Box 96)
      - Times Books, 1981-1988 (Box 96)
    - Credits, 1976, undated (Box 96)
    - Early drafts, undated (Box 96)
    - Farms, 1977-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Final blow, 1974-1982, undated (Box 96)
    - Floods, 1975-1983, 1988-1989, undated (Box 96)
    - "Glory," 1974-1981, undated (Box 97)
    - Grand Canyon, 1969-1970, 1980, undated (Box 97)
    - Grenville, Quebec, Canada, undated (Box 97)
    - Gulf of Mexico, 1978-1982 (Box 97)
    - Hatcher figures and alternatives, 1969-1973, 1981-1983, undated (Box 97)
    - Hawaii, undated (Box 97)
    - Ice age features, 1962-1983, 1992, undated (Box 97)
    - Ice ages, 1978-1981, undated (Box 97)
    - Impact sites, 1981-1983 (Box 97)
    - Impacts, 1978 (Box 97)
    - Industrial landmarks, 1975-1987 (Box 97)
    - Introduction, 1982, undated (Box 97)
    - Irrigation, 1976-1983, undated (Box 97)
    - Itineraries, 1970-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 98)
    - Karsts, 1967, 1978-1983, undated (Box 98)
    - The Look of Our Land; an Airphoto Atlas of the Rural United States compiled by Simon Baker and Henry W. Dill, Jr., 1971 (Box 98)
    - Maps (Box 98)
      - Canadian Rockies and California, 1972, 1979 (Box 98)
      - Carolina slate belt, undated (Box 98)
      - Connecticut, 1966-1967 (Box 98)
      - Miscellany, 1934, 1955, 1967-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 98, Box 99)
      - Moraines and lobes, Cape Cod, Mass. to New York City, N.Y., 1980, undated (Box 99)
      - Oregon geology, 1977-1979 (Box 99)
      - New Hampshire plutons, 1971, undated (Box 99)
      - Spokane Flood, 1983, undated (Box 99)
      - Texas, 1957-1959, 1977 (Box 99)
    - Marketing, 1974-1986, (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - Meanders, 1966, 1972-1983, undated (Box 99)
    - Miscellany, 1967, 1974-1979 (Box 100)
    - New England, 1968-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - New Mexico and Arizona, 1934, 1979-1982, undated (Box 100)
    - Photographs and illustrations (Box 100)
      - "Active" file, 1982-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 100)
      - Checkerboard, undated (Box 100)
      - Farms, 1946-1947, 1954-1971, undated (Box 100)
      - Geographical photograph duplicates, 1954-1963, 1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 101)
      - Hawaii, 1967, 1982, undated (Box 101)
      - Ice, undated See also Container OV 2, same title (Box 101)
      - Ice, glaciers, scablands, 1952, 1982, undated (Box 101)
      - Impacts, 1983, undated (Box 101)
      - Industries and suburbia, 1950, 1979-1980, undated (Box 101)
      - Miscellany (Box 101)
        - 1945, 1957-1959, 1966, 1976-1984, undated, (4 folders) (Box 101)
        - 1978-1983, undated, (3 folders) (Box 102)
      - Oahu, undated (Box 102)
      - Pacific plate movements, undated (Box 102)
      - Payments, 1983-1984 (Box 102)
      - Permissions, 1970, 1982-1984, (2 folders) (Box 102)
      - Photocopies, 1980-1983, undated, (1 folders) (Box 102, Box 103)
      - Plutons, undated (Box 103)
      - Rejects, 1950, 1970-1982, undated, (3 folders) (Box 103)
      - Rivers, undated (Box 103)
      - Volcanoes, 1983, undated See also Container OV 2, same title (Box 103)
      - Volcanoes and cascades, 1960, 1966, 1983, undated See also Container OV 2, same title, (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - Pioneer trails, 1975, undated (Box 103)
    - Plate tectonics, 1977-1978, 1985 (Box 103)
    - Red beds, 1973, 1980, undated (Box 104)
    - Reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 104)
    - Rifting, undated (Box 104)
    - Rivers, 1976-1983, undated (Box 104)
    - Rocky Mountains, 1962, 1971, 1979-1982, undated, (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - Teays River, 1970, 1979, undated (Box 104)
    - Terranes, 1980-1982, undated See also Container OV 4, same title (Box 104)
    - Titles, 1981, undated (Box 104)
    - Update, 1988-1991 (Box 104)
    - Urban/suburban, 1980-1983, undated (Box 104)
    - White Mountains, undated (Box 104)
    - Winds, 1976-1983 (Box 105)
    - Yellowstone National Park, 1973-1982, 1989, undated (Box 105)
  - New York Times Encyclopedic Almanac, "Science Fiction," 1970 (Box 105)
  - New York Times Guide to Mars (unpublished), contributor, 1985, undated (Box 105)
  - New York Times Guide to the Return of Halley's Comet, contributor, 1985 (Box 105)
  - Our Frozen Future (unpublished), 1970-1971 (Box 105)
  - The Polar Regions; the Geography, Climate, and Life of the Arctic and Antarctic, and the Explorers and Scientists who Discovered Them, 1963, undated (Box 105)
  - Quest for a Continent: The Story of the Antarctic (Box 105)
    - Appendices, undated (Box 105)
    - Argentina, 1946-1955 (Box 105)
    - Australia, 1947-1955 (Box 105)
    - Bibliography, 1955, undated (Box 105)
    - Claims, 1948-1956 (Box 105)
    - Conclusion, 1946-1947, 1955-1956, undated (Box 105)
    - Corrections, circa 1956 (Box 105)
    - Correspondence (Box 105)
      - American Polar Society and Scott Polar Reserach Institute, 1955-1956 (Box 105)
      - Balsley, J. R., 1955 (Box 105)
      - Byrd, Richard E., 1947, 1955-1956 (Box 106)
      - General, 1946-1948, 1954-1957, (4 folders) (Box 106)
      - Permissions and general, 1954-1957, (2 folders) (Box 106)
      - Siple, Paul, 1955-1956 (Box 106)
    - Draft (Box 106)
      - Complete, circa 1954, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 106, Box 107)
      - "Ice Age in Being," 1955, undated (Box 107)
      - Introduction, undated, (2 folders) (Box 107)
      - Operation Highjump, circa 1956, (3 folders) (Box 107)
      - Part I, circa 1956, (2 folders) (Box 108)
      - Part II, circa 1956 (Box 108)
      - Part III, circa 1956 (Box 108)
      - Part IV, circa 1956, (2 folders) (Box 108)
      - Part V, circa 1956, (2 folders) (Box 108)
      - Part VI, circa 1956 (Box 109)
      - Part VII, circa 1956, (2 folders) (Box 109)
    - Fauna, 1954-1955, undated (Box 109)
    - Flora, 1955, undated (Box 109)
    - France, 1947-1953 (Box 109)
    - Geographic names, 1955 (Box 109)
    - Is there a continent? undated (Box 109)
    - Little America, 1955, undated (Box 109)
    - Maps, 1947-1948, 1955, undated See also Container OV 5, same title (Box 109)
    - Maud land, undated (Box 109)
    - Miscellany, 1947, 1955-1957, undated, (2 folders) (Box 109)
    - Notebooks, 1955, undated (Box 109)
    - Operation Highjump (Box 109)
      - Clippings and letters, 1946-1947 (Box 109)
      - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 109)
      - Highjump east, 1947, 1956, undated (Box 110)
      - Messages, 1946-1947 (Box 110)
      - Miscellany, 1946-1955, undated, (2 folders) (Box 110)
      - Notes and original articles, circa 1946-1947, (2 folders) (Box 110)
      - Original articles, circa 1947, (2 folders) (Box 110)
      - Task Force 39, 1947, undated (Box 110)
      - Transmitted texts, 1946-1947 (Box 111)
    - Pack, 1948-1955, undated (Box 111)
    - Palmer Peninsula, 1946-1955 (Box 111)
    - Penguins, 1953, undated (Box 111)
    - Photographs, 1946, 1956-1957, undated (Box 111)
    - Reviews and clippings, 1957-1958, 1963-1964, (2 folders) (Box 111)
    - Ronne, Finn, 1947-1948 (Box 111)
    - U. S. Antarctic Service, undated (Box 111)
    - USS Atka (AGB-3), 1954-1957, undated, (3 folders) (Box 111)
  - Scientists at Work, contributor, 1978-1979 (Box 112)
  - Soviet Union: The Fifty Years, contributor (Box 112)
    - 1962-1967, undated, (7 folders) (Box 112)
    - 1967-1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box 113)
  - We Are Not Alone: The Search for Intelligent Life on Other Worlds and We Are Not Alone: The Continuing Search for Extraterrestial Intelligence (Box 113)
    - Adaptive optics, 1987-1992 (Box 113)
    - Bibliographies, 1964, 1974-1990, (2 folders) (Box 113)
    - Can they visit? 1973-1980 (Box 113)
    - Celestial syntax, 1966, 1972-1977, 1983-1987, undated (Box 113)
    - Communication technique, 1960-1963, undated (Box 113)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1968, 1991-1994, (2 folders) (Box 114)
    - Dyson civilizations, 1966-1969, 1979 (Box 114)
    - Edition one draft, circa 1964, (2 folders) (Box 114)
    - Edition two (Box 114)
      - Draft, circa 1992, (3 folders); (9 folders); (8 folders); (6 folders) (Box 115, Box 116, Box 117)
      - Inserts, corrections, deletions, circa 1992 (Box 117)
      - Rights and permissions, 1992-1993 (Box 117)
    - Galaxy, 1959-1962, undated (Box 117)
    - Geocentric, undated (Box 117)
    - Green Bank conference, 1963, undated (Box 117)
    - Illustrations, 1992-1993 (Box 117)
    - Infrared astronomy, 1962-1966, 1976, 1983-1992, undated (Box 118)
    - Intelligent life in the universe, 1955, 1963-1964, 1975-1978, undated (Box 118)
    - Interstellar molecules, 1970, 1984 (Box 118)
    - Interstellar probes, 1968-1973, undated (Box 118)
    - Interstellar travel, 1966, 1972-1987, (4 folders) (Box 118)
    - Introduction, 1962, undated (Box 119)
    - Jet Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, Calif., 1961-1963 (Box 119)
    - Mars (planet), 1959-1992, undated, (5 folders) (Box 119)
    - Masers, 1970, 1983-1988 (Box 119)
    - Meteorite life, 1959-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 120)
    - Meteorites, 1966, 1992 (Box 120)
    - Miscellany (Box 120)
      - 1960-1993, undated See also Container OV 2 and OV 3, same title, (4 folders) (Box 120)
      - 1993, undated, (2 folders) (Box 121)
    - Origin of life (Box 121)
      - Evolution, 1987-1994, undated (Box 121)
      - Fox, Sidney, 1963-1964 (Box 121)
      - Miller, Stanley, 1963-1967, 1991 (Box 121)
      - Miscellany, 1961-1970, 1977-1981, 1987-1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 121)
      - Organic compounds in meteorites, 1964-1992, (2 folders) (Box 121)
      - Panspermia, 1973-1992 (Box 122)
      - Ponnamperuma, Cyril, 1963-1965 (Box 122)
      - Prigogine, Ilya, 1973, 1989-1991, undated (Box 122)
      - Update, 1970, 1981-1992 (Box 122)
    - Other channels, 1970-1991 (Box 122)
    - Outline, undated (Box 122)
    - Planet detection, 1969-1991, (2 folders) (Box 122)
    - Planet hunting, 1973-1992 (Box 122)
    - Planet search by direct optical imaging, 1976, undated (Box 122)
    - Project Cyclops, 1971, 1977, undated (Box 122)
    - Project Ozma, 1960-1966, 1973-1979, 1991-1992, undated, (3 folders) (Box 123)
    - Pulsar planets, 1991-1992 (Box 123)
    - Religious and philosophical implications, 1951, 1962-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 123)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1964-1967 See also Container OV 3, same title, (4 folders) (Box 123)
    - Revisions, 1964, undated (Box 124)
    - Science reborn, 1962, undated (Box 124)
    - Serialization, Houston Post, 1965 (Box 124)
    - Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) (Box 124)
      - Columbus Day, Oct. 12, 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 124)
      - "Dead" file, 1961-1965, 1972-1997, undated, (5 folders) (Box 124)
      - Eavesdropping, 1966, 1978-1979, 1985 (Box 124)
      - International, 1975-1990 (Box 124)
      - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1977, 1984-1988 (Box 125)
      - Interstellar scintillation, undated (Box 125)
      - Meetings, Byurakan, Soviet Union, 1971-1976 (Box 125)
      - Miscellany, 1974-1994, (4 folders) (Box 125)
      - Music, 1976, undated (Box 125)
      - Outgoing messages, 1974-1977 (Box 125)
      - Record of tries, 1976, 1984 (Box 125)
      - Serendip, 1977, 1983, 1992 (Box 125)
      - Skeptics, 1972-1991, (1 folder) (Box 125, Box 126)
      - Soviet Union, 1964, 1975-1979, 1987, undated (Box 126)
      - Update, 1991-1994 (Box 126)
    - Solar system origin, 1963-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 126)
    - Television specials, 1965-1966 (Box 126)
    - Titles, undated (Box 126)
    - Travel limitations, 1975 (Box 126)
    - Update, 1971-1976, 1987-1993 (Box 126)
    - What if we succeed? (Box 126)
      - 1962-1965, 1972-1979, 1987-1992, (2 folders) (Box 126)
      - 1967-1972, 1992, undated (Box 127)
    - Where are they? 1977-1984, 1993 (Box 127)
  - Voyage of the Beagle by Charles Darwin, introduction, 1970-1973, undated (Box 127)
- Newspaper and Magazine Files, 1938-1995 (Box 127-169)
  This series comprises clippings of articles written by Sullivan, mostly from 1969 to 1981. The earliest articles mostly focus on politics, especially in relation to the Korean War, the Cold War, and the United Nations. Starting in the late 1950s, the articles begin to focus more on science, including exploration of outer space and Antarctica, then branching further into topics related to astronomy, seismology, tectonics, oceanography, and climatology. The bulk of the foreign correspondent materials relate to Sullivan’s time as a correspondent in China. They comprise alphabetical files and copy on labor, trade, land reform, and politics around the time of the People’s Republic of China revolution of 1949. The bulk of the series contains raw copy of articles with Sullivan's edits and annotations. These materials were received in bundles, mostly undated. As a result, they are grouped together in the order they appeared in the original boxes. The series also contains magazine and journal articles published in Free World, Eastern Survey, Foreign Affairs, Everybody’s, Physics Today, Arctic, and Oceans reflecting many of the same topics Sullivan explored in his books and articles. Articles from the Yale Literary Magazine include music reviews written by Sullivan in the late 1930s. Near the end of the series are lists of story ideas and proposals.
  Writings, clippings, articles, subject files, notes, periodicals, obituaries.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or material type
  - Foreign correspondent files, China (Box 127)
    - Alphabetical file (Box 127)
      - Agriculture, 1949 (Box 127)
      - Army, 1948-1949 (Box 127)
      - Bandit suppression, 1949 (Box 127)
      - Beijing (formerly Peking), 1949 (Box 127)
      - Biographies, 1947-1950 (Box 127)
      - Blockade, 1949 (Box 127)
      - Central People's Government of Communist China, 1949 (Box 127)
      - Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference, 1949, (2 folders) (Box 127)
      - Commodity prices, 1948-1949 (Box 128)
      - Communist Party of China, 1947-1949 (Box 128)
      - Congresses, 1949-1950 (Box 128)
      - Constitution, 1947-1948 (Box 128)
      - Cooperatives, 1948-1950 (Box 128)
      - Cotton, 1948-1949 (Box 128)
      - Courts, 1949 (Box 128)
      - Education, 1948-1949 (Box 128)
      - Foreign relations, 1946-1950 (Box 128)
      - Forestry, 1948-1949 (Box 128)
      - Interviews, 1949 (Box 128)
      - Labor, 1948-1950, (1 folder) (Box 128, Box 129)
      - Land reform, 1949-1950, undated, (2 folders) (Box 129)
      - Manchuria, 1947-1949 (Box 129)
      - Marxism, 1949-1950 (Box 129)
      - Miscellany, 1947-1950, undated, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 129, Box 130)
      - Missionaries, 1948-1949 (Box 130)
      - Peace talks, 1949 (Box 130)
      - Propaganda, 1949 (Box 130)
      - Political parties, 1949 (Box 130)
      - Press, 1949 (Box 130)
      - Public utilities, 1948-1949 (Box 130)
      - Railroads, 1949, undated (Box 130)
      - Rice, 1948-1949 (Box 130)
      - Shanghai, 1948-1949, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 130, Box 131)
      - Shipping, 1949 (Box 131)
      - Sino-Soviet relations, 1949-1950 (Box 131)
      - Socialization, 1949-1950 (Box 131)
      - South Bound Service Corps, 1949 (Box 131)
      - Strategy, 1949-1950 (Box 131)
      - Taiwan, 1948-1949 (Box 131)
      - Tibet Autonomous Region, 1948-1949 (Box 131)
      - Trade, 1948-1949, (3 folders) (Box 131)
      - United Nations, 1947-1949 (Box 131)
      - U. S. Information Service, 1949, undated (Box 131)
      - Women, 1949-1950 (Box 131)
      - Xinjiang Uygur Zizhiqu, 1949 (Box 131)
      - Youth, 1948-1950 (Box 131)
      - Zedong, Mao, 1944-1950 (Box 131)
    - Checklist, clippings, notes, 1950 (Box 132)
    - Copy (Box 132)
      - General, 1949 (Box 132)
      - Hong Kong, 1949-1950, (2 folders) (Box 132)
      - Shanghai, 1948-1950, (2 folders) (Box 132)
      - Siege of Shanghai, 1949 (Box 132)
    - Notes, circa 1948-1950 (Box 132)
    - Periodicals, 1949-1950 (Box 132)
  - Magazine and journal articles (Box 132)
    - 1938-1939, 1946-1950, 1957-1969, (2 folders) (Box 132)
    - 1970, 1976, 1985-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 133)
  - New York Times (Box 133)
    - Articles (Box 133)
      - 1950, 1954-1969, (10 folders) (Box 133)
      - 1969, 1971-1974, (8 folders) (Box 134)
      - 1975-1981, (8 folders) (Box 135)
      - 1982-1987, (7 folders) (Box 136)
      - 1988-1994, (5 folders) (Box 137)
    - Features, 1961-1974 (Box 137)
    - Miscellany, 1977, undated (Box 137)
    - Operation Deep Freeze II transmitted copy, 1977, undated (Box 137)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 137)
    - "Science of the Times," 1980-1982, undated (Box 137)
  - Obituaries (Box 137)
    - Dicke, Robert H., 1994-1995 (Box 137)
    - Field, William Osgood, 1994-1995 (Box 137)
    - Gardner, Beatrix, 1995 (Box 137)
    - Hoyle, Fred, 1992-1995 (Box 137)
    - Korff, Serge Alexander, 1990-1992, undated (Box 138)
    - Purcell, Edward Mill, 1994, undated (Box 138)
    - Sommel, Henry, M., 1992 (Box 138)
    - Teller, Edward, 1994 (Box 138)
  - Raw copy and drafts (Box 138)
    - Book reviews, undated (Box 138)
    - Chronological See also Digital Files, same title (Box 138)
      - 1957-1961, 1967, undated, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 138, Box 139, Box 140)
      - 1957-1962, 1970, undated, (1 folder); (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 140, Box 141, Box 142, Box 143)
      - 1957-1959, 1967-1971, undated, (3 folders) (Box 143, Box 144, Box 145)
      - 1959-1961, 1977-1979, undated, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 146, Box 147, Box 148)
      - 1962-1971, undated, (3 folders) (Box 149, Box 150, Box 151)
      - 1963-1970, undated, (3 folders) (Box 152, Box 153, Box 154)
      - 1967-1974, undated, (3 folders) (Box 155, Box 156, Box 157)
      - 1968-1976, undated, (3 folders) (Box 158, Box 159, Box 160)
      - 1972-1977, undated, (3 folders) (Box 161, Box 162, Box 163)
      - 1980s, undated, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 164, Box 165)
      - undated, (2 folders); (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 165, Box 166, Box 167)
    - Earthquake prediction, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 167)
    - Energy, stories from Europe, 1973 (Box 167)
    - Europe, 1970-1971, (2 folders) (Box 167)